# Hernan Hernandez Hernandez

London, SE1

Email: <a href="mailto:hhernandez.dev@gmail.com">hhernandez.dev@gmail.com</a>
Mobile: 07401965599

Portfolio | GitHub | LinkedIn

## **Personal Profile**

MSc in International Business with over 10 years' operations and facilities management experience in high end banking sector. However, I have always had a keen interest in technology and computers, hence, I decided to dive in the world of Software Development, something that I am truly passionate about.

Recently graduated from a Software Development Bootcamp where I worked on a considerable number of projects using web technology (HTML/CSS/Bootstrap) and programming languages such JavaScript and Python. These experiences have enabled me to gain expertise on front-end and backend development.

I am seeking an opportunity to work as a Junior Developer in a challenging environment to learn and gain more experience and further my career in this field.

# **Education and IT Training**

May 2023 / Present Just IT Training Ltd, London

**Digital Skills Bootcamp: Software Development** 

Twelve weeks intensive bootcamp covering the fundamentals of

Web and Software development.

Sep 2015 Jan 2017 Ulster University, MSc International Business

Jul 2005- Oct 2010 Universidad Nacional de Colombia, Medellin, Colombia

**BA Economics** 

#### **Tech Skills**

Web Technology: HTML5, CSS3 & JavaScript

Programming Languages: JavaScript and Python

Database Management System: MySQL

### Projects developed during bootcamp:

- Mockup Bank landing page using HTML/ CSS.
- Birthday countdown/ Christmas countdown/ Quiz App using HTML / CSS/ JavaScript.
- Inventory System / Music Database using HTML / CSS/ Python / MySQL

## **Other Skills**

- Problem solving and debugging skills
- Strong attention to detail and ability to work in a team.
- Business to business relationships
- Fluent in Spanish and English

# **Employment History**

### **ISS Facility Services**

Campus Manager for Coutts & Private Banking

June 2019 to May 2023

- Secured and maintained business contracts with clients for over 8 years by building rapport and good business to business relationships.
- Built rapport with clients and customers resulting in long standing relationships ensuring an extension of the contract for more than 8 years.
- Managed contractors and suppliers in an efficient manner complying with their respective contractual obligations.
- Successfully managed a portfolio of approx. 1 million British pounds demonstrated in excellent management on staff and consumables expenditure.
- Implemented a new cleaning scheme within the NatWest Contract achieving reductions cost by 20%.
- Ensured all the health and safety regulations were implemented correctly with the campus. Not a single accident occurred while managing the team.

# **ISS Facility Services**

Site Manager, Coutts Bank

October 2017 to June 2019

- Responsible for all day-to-day aspects relating to the management and maintenance of the cleaning service within the contract specification.
- Responsible for work allocation to the cleaning team, keeping within the specified detail of the contract, the financial budget and working principles.
- Ensure a high standard of personal hygiene and appearance and general cleanliness to comply with statutory and Company regulations.
- Control and issue cleaning material ensuring stock rotation and safety in storage.
- Be aware of the condition of the equipment to ensure that all equipment is in safe working order, checked regularly and serviced. Report any faults to business manager.
- Communicate well and demonstrate a pleasant, polite, efficient, caring and friendly service to customers and clients in all areas of service, which ISS provides.
- Report any customer complaints or compliments and take some remedial action if at all.

### **Interests**

- Travelling around the world.
- Working out.
- Learning new things/languages.
- Listening to music and a good cup of coffee.

References available upon request